Whereas a clustered index is based on a primary
key field, a nonclustered index can be based on
any other field. Nonclustered indexes are used
to speed up queries, but this comes at a cost
as each nonclustered index adds another way to
store information in a table, which adds size
to the table. Take a look at this BikeRepairs
table. Which column, besides the BikeRepairID,
is the most likely to be used as criteria in
a query? The CustomerID field is very likely,
so let's index that column. I have an INDEX
statement open here, and as you can see,
creating a nonclustered index takes little
text. First, we have a CREATE INDEX command
and a name. Then, the keyword ON is used to get us
to the table on which this index will be created.
Then in parentheses, we have the column
being indexed. I will execute this statement,
and just like that, we have both a clustered and
nonclustered index in this BikeRepairs table.